[
  {
    "question": "All of the following designs appear in Land Marks (Foot Prints) EXCEPT",
    "a": "a map of Vieques",
    "b": "depictions of historical events",
    "c": "written text",
    "d": "indigenous cultural symbols",
    "e": "symbols of peace",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "The composition of Land Marks (Foot Prints) suggests a sense of",
    "a": "movement",
    "b": "imbalance",
    "c": "hierarchy",
    "d": "isolation",
    "e": "uniformity",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following descriptions BEST represents the people depicted in The Fourth World?",
    "a": "indigenous warriors defending their land",
    "b": "European settlers posing as indigenous hunters",
    "c": "indigenous leaders holding religious ceremonies",
    "d": "European explorers mapping out uncharted territories",
    "e": "indigenous artisans creating traditional artwork",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which medium did Kent Monkman use to create The Fourth World?",
    "a": "acrylic on canvas",
    "b": "ink on vellum",
    "c": "watercolor on paper",
    "d": "charcoal on paper",
    "e": "oil on canvas",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "The background of The Fourth World highlights the",
    "a": "complexity of ecological systems",
    "b": "destruction caused by colonization",
    "c": "resilience of Indigenous communities",
    "d": "looming threat of industrialization",
    "e": "awe-inspiring beauty of the natural world",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "What type of color palette did Bonnie Devine use in Battle for the Woodlands?",
    "a": "muted tones",
    "b": "pastel colors",
    "c": "neon colors",
    "d": "cool tones",
    "e": "earthy tones",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "How did Devine showcase her indigenous heritage in Battle for the Woodlands?",
    "a": "by incorporating indigenous languages and storytelling techniques",
    "b": "by using traditional indigenous materials like beads and animal hides",
    "c": "by including portraits of famous indigenous warriors and leaders",
    "d": "by depicting deities and sacred symbols from indigenous religions",
    "e": "by featuring an indigenous map of North America rather than a colonial one",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which type of perspective did Will Wilson use to frame the subject of Church Rock Spill Evaporation Ponds?",
    "a": "two-point perspective",
    "b": "aerial view",
    "c": "isometric perspective",
    "d": "worm’s eye view",
    "e": "panoramic view",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "What conclusion can the viewer draw from the appearance of the ponds in Church Rock Spill Evaporation Ponds?",
    "a": "The algae blooms highlight the harmful effects of nutrient pollution.",
    "b": "The murky appearance of the water suggests that harmful pollutants are present.",
    "c": "The lack of visible plastic waste floating in the ponds suggests minimal pollution.",
    "d": "The presence of wildlife indicates that the ponds are part of a thriving ecosystem.",
    "e": "The stillness of the water suggests a lack of human activity in the area.",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "The background of Church Rock Spill Evaporation Ponds features a(n)",
    "a": "coastal beach",
    "b": "bustling city",
    "c": "lush forest",
    "d": "rugged mountain range",
    "e": "arid desert",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following artistic techniques is visible in Wheatfield—A Confrontation?",
    "a": "aerial perspective",
    "b": "impasto",
    "c": "pointillism",
    "d": "chiaroscuro",
    "e": "sfumato",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which element creates a focal point at the center of Wheatfield—A Confrontation?",
    "a": "a woman standing alone in the field",
    "b": "a scarecrow watching over the field",
    "c": "a wooden sign protesting urban development",
    "d": "a small group of children playing in the field",
    "e": "a patch of wild sunflowers amidst the wheat",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "How did Agnes Denes create a sense of contrast in Wheatfield—A Confrontation?",
    "a": "by juxtaposing the simplicity of agricultural work with the complexity of urban infrastructure",
    "b": "by juxtaposing the vibrant golden field against the muted grays and blues of the background",
    "c": "by contrasting the emptiness of the field against a bustling urban cityscape",
    "d": "by juxtaposing the vast scope of the field against the confined spaces of city blocks",
    "e": "by contrasting the natural sunlight on the field against the artificial light of the city",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which material did Noah Purifoy use to make Offshore Drilling?",
    "a": "scrap metal",
    "b": "PVC pipes",
    "c": "wire mesh",
    "d": "driftwood",
    "e": "concrete",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following qualities does NOT accurately describe Offshore Drilling?",
    "a": "angular",
    "b": "symmetrical",
    "c": "textured",
    "d": "large",
    "e": "abstract",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following artworks is the LARGEST?",
    "a": "Caribou Migration I",
    "b": "Marat (Sebastião)",
    "c": "Church Rock Spill Evaporation Ponds",
    "d": "The Fourth World",
    "e": "Snoopy—Early Sun Display on Earth",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "Caribou Migration I is a(n)",
    "a": "painting",
    "b": "sculpture",
    "c": "installation",
    "d": "photograph",
    "e": "collage",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following features MOST strongly emphasizes the grandeur of the natural world in Caribou Migration I?",
    "a": "the rugged texture of the mountains",
    "b": "the unique character of each caribou",
    "c": "the vastness of the landscape",
    "d": "the intricate patterns of rock formations",
    "e": "the diversity of the vegetation",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "How is Caribou Migration I similar to Church Rock Spill Evaporation Ponds?",
    "a": "They highlight the beauty of nature.",
    "b": "They include depictions of wildlife.",
    "c": "They feature geometric shapes.",
    "d": "They have a muted color palette.",
    "e": "They use aerial views.",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "How is each pond differentiated in Shrimp Farm?",
    "a": "by border design",
    "b": "by color",
    "c": "by shape",
    "d": "by lighting condition",
    "e": "by size",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following artworks is MOST similar in appearance and subject matter to Shrimp Farm?",
    "a": "Church Rock Spill Evaporation Ponds",
    "b": "Land Mark (Foot Prints)",
    "c": "Sun Tunnels",
    "d": "Offshore Drilling",
    "e": "Untilled",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the subject of Marat (Sebastião)?",
    "a": "a catadore collecting trash",
    "b": "a woman reading a book",
    "c": "a man lying in a bathtub",
    "d": "an artisan weaving a basket",
    "e": "a landscape of a coastal beach",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "The background of Marat (Sebastião) features all of the following items EXCEPT",
    "a": "paintbrushes",
    "b": "food waste",
    "c": "rubber tires",
    "d": "trash bags",
    "e": "bottles and cans",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "Rhine Water Purification Plant regularly pumps water into a(n)",
    "a": "elliptical porcelain basin",
    "b": "circular steel reservoir",
    "c": "triangular wooden cistern",
    "d": "spherical polymer drum",
    "e": "rectangular Plexiglass prism",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "How did Hans Haacke incorporate the natural environment into Rhine Water Purification Plant?",
    "a": "by growing algae in the water",
    "b": "by covering the base of the tank with natural sediment",
    "c": "by placing live goldfish in the water",
    "d": "by lining the tank with natural rocks and stones",
    "e": "by installing planters with live aquatic vegetation around the exhibit",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "The window beside Rhine Water Purification Plant presents a view of",
    "a": "the museum’s outdoor garden",
    "b": "a pathway winding through a wooded area",
    "c": "the riverbank of the Rhine River",
    "d": "a sculpture in the museum’s courtyard",
    "e": "a bustling city square",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which material appears MOST prominently in Sun Tunnels?",
    "a": "glass",
    "b": "wood",
    "c": "steel",
    "d": "marble",
    "e": "concrete",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Sun Tunnels, how do the structures interact with the natural environment?",
    "a": "They reflect the sun and the surrounding desert landscape.",
    "b": "They cast distinctive shadows in the sand.",
    "c": "They align with the movement of the sun across the sky.",
    "d": "They create a cooling effect in the desert heat.",
    "e": "They change color with exposure to light and temperature.",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which element creates a focal point in A Meter of Jungle?",
    "a": "the butterfly wings strewn along the ground",
    "b": "the square of orange tape on the ground",
    "c": "the intricate spider web hanging from a tree",
    "d": "the red markings on the tree bark",
    "e": "the cluster of blooming orchids",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "What colors appear MOST prominently in A Meter of Jungle?",
    "a": "black and white",
    "b": "green and brown",
    "c": "red and orange",
    "d": "blue and purple",
    "e": "yellow and pink",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  }
]